Let me show you why we achieved a really, really important step.
现在 我们来到了非常、非常重要的一步 我来说一下为什么
First, I rewrite the second term over here in this way,
首先 我把这里的第二项这么改写一下
where I split x_1 to t minus one,
我把 Xt-1 分成
to z_t minus one,
Zt-1 和
and z_1 to t minus two.
Z1:t-2
If you compare this with our formula from the very beginning over here,
把这个和刚开始的这个公式对比
you can see that this term here is
你可以看到 这里的这一项
exactly the belief from the previous timestep, t minus one.
就是前一个时间步 t-1 的信仰
Now, we can rewrite the integral with a belief x_t minus one inside.
现在 我们在积分内部使用 bel(Xt-1)
The amazing thing is,
神奇的是
that we have a recursive update formula.
我们得到了一个递归的更新公式
You use to estimate its state from
你使用这个公式 根据前面的时间步
the previous timestep for the prediction of the current one.
估算它的状态 从而预测当前状态
This is one of the most important steps as a recursive Bayesian filter
这是递归贝叶斯滤波器中的最重要步骤之一
because we are independent from the whole observation and control history.
因为我们独立于整个观察和控制历史
So, in the graph structure,
因此 在图形结构里
I replace this part over here with the belief x_t minus one.
我使用 bel(Xt-1) 替代这部分
Finally, you can replace the integral by a sum over all
最后 你可以替代使用所有 Xi 上的总和来替换
x_i's because you have a discrete localization scenario in this case.
这个积分 因为在本例中有一个离散的定位场景
By the way, you already saw this formula in Sebastian's lesson for localization.
顺便说一下 你之前在Sebastian 的课上已经看到过这个公式
The process of predicting x_t with the previous beliefs,
使用之前的信仰 Xt-1 和转换模型来
x_t minus one, and the transition model is technically a convolution.
预测Xt 的过程 在技术上被称作卷积
Now, you also know the full mathematical background and how to derive this module.
现在 你已经知道了全部的数学背景 以及如何推演这个模型
If you take a look to the formula again,
如果你再看看这个公式
it is essential that the belief at x_t
你会发现 在 Xt 处的信仰等于0
equals zero is initialized with meaningful assumption.
必须使用有意义的假设初始化
It depends on the localization scenario how you set the belief,
它取决于你在定位场景中你如何设置信仰
or in other words, how you initialize your filter.
换句话说 如何初始化你的滤波器
For example, you can use GPS to get a course estimate where you are.
例如 你可以使用 GPS 来大致估算你的位置
So, let's sum up to this point.
我们总结一下
You learned again, how to apply the law of
你再次学习了如何在应用
total probability by including the new variable, x_t minus one.
全概率的公式的时候包括新的变量 Xt-1
You also learned about the Markov Assumption,
你还了解了马尔可夫假设
which is very important for probabilistic reasoning.
这个假设对概率推理非常重要
And finally, you learned how to derive the recursive filter structure.
最后 你学习了如何推演递归滤波器结构
Next, you will implement a motion model in C++.
接下来 你要在 C++ 中实现一个运动模型
You will also learn how to initialize our localizer,
你还需要学习如何初始化定位器
which means, defining the belief of the state at the very beginning.
也就是确定刚开始对于状态的信仰
So, let's do it.
好的 我们开始吧